Register of the Joseph C. Trainor papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers (SCAP). General Headquarters (GHQ). Civil Information and Education Section (CIE) File, 1943-1952
  - Research and Information Division
    - Japanese Middle Schools, A Survey of Students and Teachers. Special report, 1946 March 4
    - Japanese Research Institutions, Consolidation of Reports on. Report, 1947 February
    - Japanese teachers' length of service. Statistical tables, 1946 April 13
    - Japanese women's organizations. List, 1946 April
    - Ministry of Education
      - Annual Reports - Statistical Tables. Special report, 1946 March 8
      - Directives and instructions. Check sheet, 1946 April 29
    - National Educational Personnel Labor Union - Constitution. Translation, 1946 April 15
    - National Teachers' Union of Japan, A Report on. Special report, 1946 March 2
    - Newly Elected Women Members of the Diet. Statistical report, 1946 April 18
    - Plan of research for educational research unit. Report, undated
    - School Hygiene in Japan. Special report, 1946 April 12
    - Student Expenses. Special report, 1946 May 16
    - Teacher Indoctrination Institutes. Special report, 1946 March 12
    - Teacher Retirement in Japan. Special report, 1946 May 3
    - Teachers' Salary Campaign, A Calendar of. Special report, 1947 January 10
    - Teachers' Training in Tohoku Imperial University. Special report, 1947 February 20
    - Tokyo Teachers' Union, Regulations of. Special report, 1946 March 4
    - Women's Legal Status in Japan. Special report, 1946 March 11
  - Research Unit. Education Branch
    - Roster of Higher Educational Institutions in Japan. Information memorandum to parallel division, 1948 February 9
  - Economic and Scientific Section. Scientific and Technical Division
    - Science and Technology in Japan. Report No. 14, undated
    - Science and Technology in Japan. Report No. 19, 1949 April
    - Science and Technology in Japan. Report No. 20, 1948 December
- Subject File, 1933-1953
  Memoranda, reports, pamphlets, maps, reprints, notes, and other printed matter arranged alphabetically by subject or title.
  - Address by the Vice-Minister of Education at the inaugural ceremony of the Student Personnel Service Institute. Transcript, 1947 September 17 (Box 69)
  - Allied Council for Japan
    - General, 1946 October (Box 70)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1947 November
  - America-Japan Society, Tokyo, Japan - Address by Governor Thomas E. Dewey at a luncheon. Transcript, 1951 July 6
  - American Council on Education
    - Commission on the occupied areas, 1949-1950
    - Educational Progress in Japan and the Ryukyus. Report, 1950 May 25
  - American Dental Association Mission to Japan. Report, 1951 July
  - American teachers - Income tax. Tax laws and table, undated
  - Annual Report of Activities Supporting Reorientation Program in Japan and the Ryukyu Islands, 1951 July
  - The Army's Educational Exchange Program. Report, 1950 May
  - The Case for Japan, by Howard M. Bell. Report, undated
  - Census - Survey of the handicapped, 1946 April - May
  - Central labor relations board. Report, 1947 April 5
  - Chronology of the War in the Southwest Pacific, 1941 - 1945. Prepared by the Historical Division, G-3, GHQ, U.S. Army Forces, Pacific
  - Chronology of the Occupation - 15 August 1945 to 31 March 1946. Prepared by the Historical Division, G-3, GHQ, U.S. Army Forces, Pacific
  - Commission for International Educational Reconstruction, 1947 September - October
  - Community Programs in Japan. Report, draft, undated
  - Constitution of the empire of Japan, undated
  - Constitution of Japan, 1946 November
  - Creation of New Japanese Civilization, by Shigeru Nambara. Transcript of address, 1946 February 11
  - Currency (Japanese) (4 bills)
  - Development of School Library in Japan and Its Present Condition, by Tsunenobu Fukagawa. Report, 1950 October
  - Economic Problems of Students in Japan of Post-War, by Masataka Sugi. Report, 1949 June (Box 71)
  - Education for War - A Study of the Exploitation of the Japanese School System for the Propagation of Ultra-Nationalism and Militarism, undated
    - Chapters I - XIII
    - Chapters XIV - XX
  - Education Program Adopted at the 69th Annual Convention of the American Federation of Labor 1950. Houston, Texas, 1950 September 18 - 23
  - Educators' public service law, 1948 March
  - Eighth Army Headquarters - Civil education program, 1947 February
  - Eighth Army Military Governments Unit - Directory, 1947 April
  - The Far East - A Syllabus, by George L. Harris, American Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, Inc., 1942
  - Far East Command, General Headquarters - Organizational charts, 1949
  - Far East Command and the Supreme Commander of the Allied Powers, General Headquarters - Traffic and vehicle regulations, 1951 December 12
  - Farnsworth, Richard B., Ministry of Education in Lebanon, 1953
  - The Four Year Daigaku and Daikuin (Graduate School). Report, undated
  - Gist of Proposed Reform of Education and Practical Application of the Educational Reform Plan, by Chugo Wanatabe, 1946 February 21
  - Gunbatsu - Rise of Militarism. Article, 1946 July 12
  - Hellman, Richard - Interviews with members of the Imperial University, 1945
  - Hiroshima National University, plan for the establishment of, undated
  - History of Democracy in Japan, by Konishi and Toyama, undated
    - English version
    - Japanese version
  - The Ideals of Educational Reforms in Japan, by Shigeru Nambara, (President of University of Tokyo). Booklet, 1951 (Box 72)
  - Imperial Fisheries Institute (Suisan Koshujo). Pamphlet, 1933
  - India. Ministry of Education - Report of the General Cultural Scholarships Scheme, 1949-1950, undated
  - Institute for Indoctrination of Educators. Report, undated
  - Institute for Research of Democratic Educational Material and The International Educational Material Company, undated
  - Institute of International Education, 1946-1951
  - Instruction manual for two-band radio receiver, model 6000-BAC, undated
  - Introduction to Spoken Japanese. The Japanese Language School, University of Michigan, 1944
  - Japan Education Association (Nippon Kyoiku-Kai), 1946-1947
  - Japan Moves Toward Democracy, by Lt. Col. D.R. Nugent. Transcript of address, undated
  - Japan Scholarship Society, 1949-1953
  - Japan Social Work School - Outline, undated
  - Japan Student Association - Constitution, undated
  - Japan-America Student Conference, 1948
  - Japanese delegation to the U.S.A. on university education for public administration. Report, 1951 September
  - Japanese educational periodicals. List, undated
  - Japanese labor union legislation, 1945-1946
  - The Japanese Peace and Security Treaties. Text and memos, 1951 September
  - Japanese rural land reform program, undated
  - Junior College Journal, Vol. XXII, No. 1, 1951 September
  - Keio University (Tokyo), 1949-1952
  - Kodokwanki, edited by Meiji Japan Society. Tokyo, 1937 (Box 73)
  - Kyoto University - Map, 1950
  - Kyushu University - Outline, 1950
  - Laws and ordinances, miscellaneous, 1945-1952
  - Learned societies and research institutes for natural sciences in Japan. List, 1947
  - Learned societies in cultural sciences. List, undated
  - Lebanon - Technical cooperation program between the U.S. government and Lebanon, 1952
  - Library, The University and College, by Masai Watanabe. Report, 1951 October
  - Management improvement program. Report of the Far East Command, fiscal year, 1951
  - Maps
    - General, 1945-1947
    - Prefectural (English)
      - Akita - Nigata prefectures
      - Okayama - Yamanashi prefectures
    - Prefectural (Japanese)
      - Aichi - Kumamote prefectures
      - Mie - Yamanashi prefectures
    - Tourist
  - Ministry of Welfare. Medical Affairs Bureau - Medical affairs legislation in Japan, 1951 January 1 (Box 74)
  - Nara Women's University, 1949
  - National Association of Girls' High School Principals - Organization and rules, 1946 February
  - National Association of Middle School Principals - Organization and rules, 1946 February
  - National Education Association. Report, undated
  - National Federation of Teachers' Unions - Labor contract, undated
  - National Institute for Educational Research, 1948, 1950
  - New Plan of Japanese History Education. Report, undated
  - IX (Ninth) Corps. Headquarters. Office of Commanding General. - Civil education reference materials, 1948 October 28
  - Office of the U.S. Political Advisor, Tokyo, Japan
    - Educational Affairs in Japan, December 1 - 31, 1945
    - Educational Affairs in Japan, February 1 - 28, 1946
  - On Studies Made on Politics and History of America, by Yasaki Takagi, Osaka. Report, 1951
  - Osaka University, 1951
  - Osaka, the City and its Municipal Government. Booklet, 1951
  - Outline of the History of Japanese Education, by Dr. Ken Ishikawa, 1940
  - The Past and Present of Japanese Education, by Kotaro Tanaka, 1950 February
  - The Phi Delta Kappan, Vol. XXX, No. 2, 1948 October
  - Present Day Politics and Education, by Daishiro Hikada, undated
  - Problems of Engineering Education in Japan, by R. Torikai (President, Kyoto University). Report, undated
  - Ration books, coupons, stamps, undated
  - Relaxation Methods in U.S. Navy Schools, by Commander William Neufield, U.S.N.R. Reprint, 1951 August
  - Renewal committee, address to, by Dr. H. C. Kelly. Transcript, 1947 September 17
  - School Education in New Japan, compiled by Kaneo Ohta and Ichiro Taketa. Report, 1949 April
  - School lunch research committee. Report, 1950 August
  - Scientific study of Japanese history. Memorandum of conversation, 1945 October 22
  - Service center, Tokyo, undated
  - Shintoism and Buddhism Compared, undated
  - Short English Addresses, by Shigeru Nambara (President, University of Tokyo), 1949 June 5
  - Six-Three (6 - 3) System Education, by Kaoru Sato, 1951
  - Some Principles of Mass Persuasion, by Dorwin Cartwright. Reprint, 1949
  - Speech by S. Nambara at the opening ceremony of the conference of university administrators. Transcript, undated
  - Student Government in the U.S. Transcript of address, 1946 September 23
  - The Study of International Relations and Its Place in the University Curriculum, by Takashi Haruki, undated
  - Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers
    - Chief of staff - Organizational chart, 1946 January 24
    - Japanese student selected for scholarship under SCAP student program, 1949
    - Tokyo and vicinity telephone directory, 1948 April 1 (Box 75)
  - Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers. General Headquarters - Circular No. 18, 1948 June 5
  - Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers and the Far East Command
    - Official relations with foreign diplomatic missions, 1951 September 13
    - Selected Data on the Occupation of Japan, 1950
  - Survey of Romanization Problem and Romazi Education in Japan, by Kito-Reizo of Romazi-undo Honbu, 1950 September 5
  - Survey of Tokyo Normal School for Youth Teachers, 1946 July
  - Tokyo Dental College, 1950 November
  - Tokyo Imperial University
    - Calendar, 1940-1941
    - Historiographical Institute. List of publications and members, 1939 December
    - Institute of Historical Compilation, undated
  - Tokyo Kaikan Labor Agreement. Excerpts, undated
  - Toyo Kogyo Kabushiki Kaisha (construction plant in Hiroshima), 1946 December 20
  - Training for Educational Leadership in Japan, by Paul E. Webb, undated
  - UNESCO and the Universities, by Philip Shay. Transcript of address, 1947 July 26
  - UNESCO organizations in Japan, undated
  - Unitarian Service Committee, Inc. - Medical mission to Japan. Report, 1951 November 27
  - U.S. Army Forces, Pacific. General Headquarters. - Tokyo telephone directory (military)
    - 1946 June 6
    - 1946 July 4
  - U.S. Army Forces, Pacific. General Headquarters. Civil Information and Education Section - Weekly Summaries
    - 1945 December 1 - 28 (Box 76)
    - 1945 December 29 - 1946 January 26
  - U.S. Army Eighth Army - Locations and responsibilities of 8th Army military government units. Map, 1946 May 23
  - U.S. Cultural Science Mission to Japan - Report to SCAP, 1949 January
  - U.S. Department of the Army. Office of the Secretary of the Army. Office for Occupied Areas. Reorientation Branch. Semi-Annual Report of the Stateside Activities Supporting the Reorientation Program in Japan and the Ryukyu Islands, 1951 January
  - U.S. Department of State. Educational Exchanges under the Fulbright Act. Pamphlet, 1949 December
  - U.S. Department of State. Report of the United States Library to Advise on the Establishment of the National Diet Library of Japan, 1948 February 8
  - Walt Whitman Comes to the Rescue, by Victor Frene, 1946 May 9
  - "What is Group Dynamics?," by David H. Jenkins (reprint) Adult Education Journal, 1950 April
  - Zengakuren. 3rd National Conference. Waseda University, 1949 November 2 - 3
  - Miscellaneous
    - 1945-1952
    - undated